all right welcome everyone um happy
Sabbath to you I want to uh uh invite
you all to uh pray with me we're going
to get into the word of God this morning
today uh put a one in the chat if you
are ready for this word and by the way
please share this link with as many as
you can um we are about to get into a
Bible study this is going to be a bible
study on the question of the
investigative judgment and why so many
Christians reject the idea of an
investigative judgment is the
investigative judgment in the Bible um
please get your Bibles share this link
uh share share share share let's get
into the word of God we're going to
start with a word of prayer and um and
let's see what the word of God has to
say to us today amen Bible all day long
let's pray heavenly
father thank you Lord for your word
thank you Lord for your presence Lord I
want to ask in a special way that you
would please speak through this message
today especially for those Lord who may
be afraid of the idea of an
investigative judgment be with those
Lord who may be hearing this for the
first time or those who may have always
understood this but um did not quite
understand Lord please Grant your people
understanding today is our prayer in
Jesus name amen and
amen all right um why many Christians
reject the
investigative judgment we're going to go
to the screen we're already at the
screen but I want to just uh begin
uh with the question is there a judgment
is there a judgment well the Bible tells
us in 2 Corinthians chapter 5 and verse
10 we must
all appear before the Judgment seat of
Christ that everyone may receive the
things done in his body according to
that he has done whether it be good
or whether it be bad now we're just
going to I'm going to ask you a series
of questions guys as we go through this
pre through this presentation so the
first thing I want to ask you is
according to the Bible is there a
judgment in which every single person
that has ever lived will be involved in
according to the text we just read yes
or no put a one in the chat simple
question is there a judgment
that every person whether good or bad
whether Christian or non-Christian will
be a part of there should be nothing
else but a one in the chat because a one
says yes if you're reading the
Bible and you go by the Bible if you are
a solar scriptura
person the answer to this question is
obviously yes it is obviously yes
however please note with me that
according to to 1 John 4:1 17 the Bible
also says this herein is our love made
perfect that we may have boldness in the
day of judgment because as he is so are
we in this
world so the Bible tells us then that we
are not to be afraid of judgment so
number one there is a
judgment but number two if we are as
Christ is then we may have boldness in
the day of judgment put a two in the
chat if you would like to have boldness
in the day of
judgment we're told that that if our
love is made perfect we do not need to
be afraid of a
judgment we do not need to be afraid of
the Judgment so so right off the bat
everyone if if you you are a Christian
and you don't like the sound of judgment
you don't like the sound of of of
standing before the Judgment seat of
Christ something is
wrong and beloved
that that is a warning it's a warning of
Mercy that inside you know something's
not right because the text says if my
love is made perfect
I will have boldness in the day of
judgment I will not be saying oh there's
no such thing as a
judgment no no no no no no no that's not
what I'm going to be pushing that will
not be the theology I'm accepting that
there's no judgment that judgment is all
you know I don't have to wor no no no no
no my thinking according to the text
will
be I may have boldness in the day of
judgment I don't need to be afraid in
the day of judgment
judement so here is a
question or rather let me make this let
me say this as a statement let me let
the Bible say it note with me in
Deuteronomy chapter 25 verse1 where the
Bible says this if there be a
controversy between men and they come
unto the judge that the judges May judge
them then shall they justify the
righteous and condemn
the
wicked all right let me ask you a
question if you are the Righteous how do
you see this
text you see this text with
joy because what the text is saying to
the righteous is that the purpose of
judgment is in
justifying the
righteous that's according to the text
judgment justifies let me rephrase it
this way
judgment for the righteous is a
Vindication for them now y'all I know
you're at home I know I can't see you
but raise your hand if you would like to
be Vindicated by God if you would like
to be Vindicated by God himself which is
what judgment is for the
righteous then that's a good thing
judgment is a good thing for the
righteous the righteous
welcome
judgment however note with me the text
again let's go back to the
screen it says then shall they shall
justify the righteous and condemn the
wicked all right come on back how would
the wicked feel about
judgment the wicked don't want judgment
why not because it's going to condemn
them are y'all following me the
righteous want judgment because it
vindicates them the wicked do not want
judgment because it
condemns
them come on let's go back to the screen
notice with me Psalm chapter 1 Psalm
chapter 1 beginning with verse one the
Bible
says blessed is a man that walketh not
in the counsel of the ungodly nor
standeth in the way of the Sinners nor
sth in the seat of the scornful but his
Delight is in the law of the Lord and in
his law does he meditate day and night
he shall be like a tree planted by the
rivers of water that bring forth her
fruit in in his season or bring forth
his fruit in his
season his Leaf shall not shall not
wither and whatsoever he doeth shall
prosper now watch this the ungodly are
not so but are like the chaff which the
wind driveth away therefore the ungodly
shall not stand in the Judgment nor
sinners in the congregation of the
righteous for the Lord knoweth the way
of the righteous but the way of the
ungodly Shall Perish do you see that the
righteous welcome judgment but the but
the
sinner the Wicked the ungodly shall not
stand in the
Judgment so it would make sense then
that the ungodly are afraid of judgment
the ungodly don't want judgment the
ungodly don't like to hear any idea
about there being such a thing as a
judgment
the righteous on the other
hand those who are truly following
Christ on the other hand not that they
are
perfect but they know that they're
forgiven they know that they are under
the mercy of God and they understand
that God's judgment is not a thing to be
afraid of unless of course you're a part
of the
wicked come on let's go back to the
screen and I I want you to note with me
Psalm 61 Isaiah
61:8 the Bible says for I the
Lord
love
judgment I hate robbery for burnt
offering I will direct their work in
truth and I will make an Everlasting
Covenant with them I the Lord love
judgment so let me ask you should we
love what God loves
I it's just a question should we love
what God loves yes or no I think the
answer would be yes if God loves
something then we should love it too so
as Christians should we love judgment
just as God loves judgment or should we
fear and hate judgment should we despise
judgment why does God love judgment why
does God love judgment let's go back to
the screen here's why God loves
judgment the Bible says in Ecclesiastes
58 if thou seest the oppression of the
poor and violent perverting of judgment
and Justice in a province Marvel not at
the matter for he that is higher than
the highest regardeth and there be
higher than
they that is a powerful verse you
guys because what the verse is saying
and I'm sure you will catch the gist of
this
is that God is saying
listen even though Justice may be
perverted on Earth don't worry there's a
higher judge there's a higher Court
there is a supreme court in which you
can
appeal the Judgment of this
world the world may call you crazy for
following Jesus the world may call you
crazy for believing in the Bible
but God is saying one day one day
judgment my judgment is going to reverse
the decisions of the world it's going to
reverse the
conclusions of the
World by the way this is the reason why
at the end of time every knee shall bow
and every tongue confess why because of
God's judgment
the wicked will be will be brought face
to
face and will have to acknowledge the
justice of God our God is a God of
Justice our God is a god of judgment and
God looks down and he sees all the cases
in which people have been falsely
condemned people have been falsely
judged people have been falsely accused
and God says don't
worry one day the
Supreme Court of
Heaven is going to
reverse these
decisions I am going to
exonerate put that word in the chat for
me I am going to exonerate my people
people now if you are a saint of the
most high if you are a child of the most
high you should be glad for judgment
right
now you should be glad that God is
saying listen my son listen my daughter
I've watched you I've watched you be
falsely accused I've watched you be
falsely condemned I have watched and
I've seen don't think don't think my son
my daughter that I have not seen I have
seen and in my judgment everything that
was wronged and that was arrived to at a
faulty conclusion will be
publicly will be overturned for the
entire universe to see if you are a
child of God there is no way on Earth
you should be you should be fighting
against this idea of judgment unless of
course you have something to
hide unless of course you're worried
about something coming up in your
trial but we're going to come back to
that we're going to come back to that in
a moment I want you to note again with
me why God is so concerned about
judgment in Isaiah 59:14 the Bible says
and judgment is turned away backward and
Justice stand at the far off for truth
is fallen in the street and Equity
cannot
enter the Bible goes on to say in the
same book Isaiah it says woe unto them
that are Mighty to drink wine and Men of
strength to mingle strong drink which
justify the wicked for reward and take
away the righteousness of the righteous
from him in other words God is saying I
am looking down on Earth and I'm seeing
righteous people being condemned as
guilty I'm seeing true Christians being
called by other alleged Christians
saying y'all are not even
Christian I I'm seeing this false
judgment on other people on people who
are
mine I'm seeing for example in the Dark
Ages people being burned at the stake
for refusing to confess a belief that is
not biblical I'm seeing them con
condemned by human tribunals I am seeing
this don't
worry because when the Supreme Court of
Heaven
sits these judgments are going to be
overturned the condemnations of the
prophets in the past the condemnations
of the Saints in the past who were
burned at the stake for their faith all
of those condemnations that that were
that were issued in Earthly courts
will be overturned when the Supreme
Court of Heaven sits now if you're not
interested in the Supreme Court of
Heaven
sitting something's
wrong something is
wrong because the purpose of the Supreme
Court in heaven sitting is to overturn
every false judgment ever made about you
as a Christian in life it is to overturn
every every false thing that has ever
been said about God's people from the
beginning of time to the end of time it
is to convince the ungodly of their
ungodly speeches so why in the world
would a Christian not want the Supreme
Court of
Heaven to
sit that's something strange to me y'all
that doesn't make sense to
me in Isaiah 595
yay truth faileth he that departed from
Evil maketh himself a prey and the Lord
the Lord saw it and it displeased him
that there was no judgment did y'all see
that God is displeased when there is no
judgment the wicked fear judgment may I
say it plainly y'all the wicked fear
judgment the righteous do not fear
judgment note again with me Deuteronomy
27:19 cursed be he that perverteth the
Judgment of the stranger and fatherless
and Widow again Psalm 19 or Psalm 76
verse 8
and9 thou did cause judgment to be heard
from Heaven the Earth feared and was
still when God arose to judgment to save
all the meek of the earth what does the
text tell us the purpose of judgment is
to save the meek of the
earth do I need to repeat that y'all put
a one in the chat so I know you're
following the purpose of judgment is not
to condemn the righteous it is to
preserve it is to save the meek there is
not a reason on planet Earth that a
single Christian should have an issue
with the Judgment of God
there is not a single reason why a
Christian should have an issue with God
being seated in a judgment in a supreme
court of
heaven I'm just we're just reading Bible
y'all look look what Isaiah 54:17 says
this is a song that so many Christians
sing and then what yet when you talk to
them about judgment about an investig of
judgment oh that's not biblical what
does the text say here Isaiah
54:17 no weapon that is formed against
thee shall prosper and every tongue that
shall rise against
thee in judgment Thou shalt
condemn this is the heritage of the
Servants of the Lord and their
righteousness is of me say the Lord did
y'all see
that the purpose of the judgment
is for God to reverse every tongue that
has ever risen against
you every tongue that has ever falsely
accused you every tongue that has ever
spoken a lie or put out disinformation
about you to your friends to your family
online Whatever It Is God says my
son my
daughter do not worry
in the
Judgment every tongue that has lied that
has spoken ill of you that has spoken
ill of me shall be condemned so why
should a Christian suddenly be afraid of
any type of investigative judgment what
is God investigating he's investigating
to see who the Liars
are now listen
it's not that God doesn't
know the purpose of God's judgment is
not for God to to discover oh you're
righteous and you're Wicked no it's not
God knows all
things the purpose of God's judgment is
not for him it's for us it's for Angels
it's for angels that cannot read the
heart of human beings it's for men that
cannot read one another's Hearts beloved
listen to me the purpose of the Judgment
of God is not God saying H I wonder who
is righteous and who isn't the purpose
of the Judgment of God is is because we
are so easily fooled as human beings we
may look at individuals and say ah there
goes a righteous man I expect that this
righteous man will be in heaven there
goes that righteous woman I expect that
this righteous woman will be in heaven
but when they're not in heaven we're
gonna be like well what in the world H
God are you sure God I know this person
and the purpose beloved of the judgment
is for
God to
reveal truth from error to us isn't God
good I mean God could literally be like
hey y'all I know and y'all are just
going to have to trust me just trust my
word God says no I'm going to perform a
judgment and allow not only the
righteous but also the wicked
there is a reason why the wicked will
say just and true are thy ways oh king
of saints there's a reason why every
knee shall bow and every tongue confess
and the reason is because God will make
known his
judgments to the entire world that is
the reason for the judgment and there is
no
reason that any Christian on Earth
should be arguing against an
investigative judgment of God unless of
course you have something to hide
something you don't want God to see
something you don't want God to take
account
of and if that's the case God is calling
you to repent because he doesn't want
you to have fear of the Judgment he
wants you to be bold in the Judgment but
you can't be bold the reason why so many
Christians reject the Judgment you guys
is
[Music]
because what criminal do you know that
wants to go to court I'll see you in
court no no criminal wants to go to
court y'all but the person that has been
wrongly accused that is wrongly that has
been wrongly condemned that person wants
a trial that
person let's say given that the judge is
a just
judge the wrongly condemned the wrongly
blamed want a
trial see why does God have a judgment
let's go back to the screen Revelation
12:10 why does God say I am setting up a
judgment here's why because the Bible
says I heard a loud voice in heaven
saying now has come salvation and
strength and the kingdom of our God and
the power of is Christ for the accuser
of our Brethren is cast down which
accuse them before our God day and night
whoa wait a minute we got an accuser yes
beloved we have an accuser and that
accuser's name is Satan and Satan is
busy accusing every single individual
saying none of these people have a right
to go to heaven when Jesus comes again
none of them and so beloved listen to me
the
Judgment in the judgment God is
seeking to silence the accusations of
Satan he's
seeking to
overturn the crooked and faulty
judgments made by
man against his own people
he's seeking to silence the accusation
of the accuser of the Brethren why on
Earth would a Christian argue against
judgment it doesn't make
sense it doesn't add up when you
understand in the Judgment beloved that
Jesus is our defense
attorney why would you be afraid of
judgment unless of course you're
lying to your defense attorne
attorney unless of
course your defense
attorney
recognizes that your fruit are not
living up to your
profession then you got something to
worry worry
about come on Psalm 172 listen to this
y'all Psalm 172 the text says may my
Vindication this is the Study Bible
listen to it may my Vindication come
from your presence may your eyes see
what is Right beloved judgment is about
vindication and if you are Innocent by
the blood of the Lamb if you are
innocent because you've accepted Christ
you should be looking forward to
Vindication from the enemy that's what
the Judgment that Paul says we shall all
appear before the judgment say that's
what the judgment is about it is about
the Vindication of the righteous it is
about the Vindication of the meek and so
if a person is arguing against the idea
of a judgment something is wrong if a
Christian is arguing against the idea of
a judgment something is wrong note again
with me Psalm 37:27 and 28 the Bible
says depart from Evil and do good and
dwell forever more for the Lord loveth
judgment and forsaketh not his Saints
they are preserved forever but the seed
of the wicked shall be cut off do y'all
understand this do y'all understand are
y'all getting the idea of just how
important judgment is to God's people
just how important judgment is to God so
here's a question how do how do
the the um how do the righteous feel
about judgment how should the righteous
feel about judgment note with me again
on the screen Proverbs 21:15 the Bible
says it
is
Joy to the just to do judgment but
destruction shall be to the workers of
iniquity judgment is Joy to the just how
about this Psalm 26:1 Judge Me Oh Lord
for I have walked in mine Integrity I
have also trusted in the Lord therefore
I shall not slide how about this one
judge me oh Lord my God according to thy
righteousness and let not them that is
the wicked Rejoice over me how about
this one Judge Me Oh God and plead my
cause against an ungodly Nation Oh
deliver me from the deceitful and unjust
man do do y'all understand that the
purpose of the Judgment for the Saints
is to be Vindicated is to be
justified the purpose of the Judgment of
God beloved is not a scary thing if you
are walking in Christ's
righteousness
however how do the wicked view
judgment let's look at Proverbs 19:28
an ungodly witness scornest judgment and
the mouth of the wicked devoureth
iniquity wow wow wow how about this one
how about this one evil
men understand not judgment but they
that seek the Lord understand all things
do
y'all the
wicked hate judgment
let me say it again the wicked hate
judgment a and you know what it it makes
sense because if you think about it if
you think about it
um if judgment if the innocent desire
right judgment the guilty desire to
avoid
it can we say that
the innocent desire right judgment but
the guilty desire to avoid
it man if I'm guilty I don't want
judgment if I'm guilty I don't want to
go to the court because I know that if I
go to the courtroom I am going to be
condemned and sented to prison so now I
don't want judgment beloved if a
Christian is arguing against the idea of
a judgment there is an
issue it ought to tell you something
about your own life see when God is
speaking to job check out job 40:8 and
and I want you to notice this s this
this statement y'all it is so powerful
here's what it says will thou also disan
know my judgment will thou condemn me
that thou mayest be righteous here's
what God is
asking will you get rid of my judgment
will you declare that I have no no no
reason for judging so that you could be
righteous it seems to me beloved that
that's what a lot of people are doing
today a judgment no there's no such to
judgment that's not biblical why why
would that not be biblical when look at
all the verses we just looked at how is
a judgment not biblical
could it be that many Christians don't
want a judgment because they're not
living according to the light that God
has given could that be the reason why
why so many Christians reject the idea
of a judgment someone said the wicked
don't want to be called
out that's a good way to put it if
you're innocent you walk into court with
hope if you're guilty you don't want to
be in
court you don't want to be in court now
why would the why would a
Christian not want to be in court why
would a Christian not want judgment well
if there's a judgment there must be a
standard of the Judgment what do y'all
think yes or no put a one in the
chat if there is a
judgment if there's going to be a
Discerning between something that is
right and something that is wrong there
must be a standard by which to determine
what is right and what is wrong
does the bible help us know what this
standard is let's go back to the
screen and let's go to Ecclesiastes 12:2
the Bible says and further by these my
son be admonished of making many books
there is no end and much study is a
weariness of the flesh so let's
summarize the matter that's what he's
saying let's hear the conclusion of the
whole matter fear God and keep his
Commandments for this is the whole duty
of man for God shall bring every work
into what what is God going to bring
everybody every work into what judgment
with every secret thing whether it be
good or whether it be evil that's
interesting that that is that is
interesting wait a
minute God is going to bring every work
into
judgment God is going to bring every
work into judgment whether it be good or
whether it be evil yes he is and then
God says what keep my
Commandments oh so the standard of the
Judgment then is the
Commandments it's the law of God wait a
minute didn't Jesus say we're just
having a Bible study y'all okay are
y'all good with the Bible study we're
just doing Bible all day we should
hashtag that Bible all day John 14:15
Jesus said if you love me keep my
Commandments now listen y'all remember
we want boldness in the day of judgment
and God says your boldness is made
perfect by your love so if you if you
love if you love me you're G to be bold
in the Judgment you have nothing to be
afraid of okay well what does it mean to
love you Jesus oh Jesus said if you love
me keep my Commandments now hold on for
a second
y'all because I hear some of you right
now well which Commandments okay let's
not even talk about that right now let's
just say
if something came out of Jesus's
mouth let's just say that's his
Commandments whatever that is it could
be make sure you eat peanut butter let's
just say it's make sure you eat peanut
butter what I need you to understand
beloved is that if if if the Commandment
is make sure you eat peanut
butter that's the
standard by which God is going to judge
who loves me and who doesn't it's like
Simon Says Simon Says stand up remember
the game Simon Says y'all you only obey
what Simon says but if he doesn't say it
then you don't
obey but Simon Says shows your loyalty
to Simon Just Like Jesus says shows your
loyalty to Jesus so we're not even
talking about the fact that the
Commandments he's speaking about are the
Commandments that he wrote with his own
finger back on Mount Si there's a
beautiful book called The deity of
Christ the book is named the deity of
Christ uh I believe it's written by a
Baptist pastor and I'm I mentioned it in
my in my presentation last Sunday uh the
15 fact check presentation go back if
you haven't seen it but in that
presentation in that
book the author is showing how Jesus is
all over the Old Testament he's the
angel of the Lord he is the angel that
appeared in the burning bush to Moses
and then he says he is the one that from
Mount Si wrote The Law of God therefore
the Ten Commandments are Jesus's
Commandments now Jesus said beloved if
you love me if you love me keep my
commandments so if the Commandments are
the standard of the of the judgment and
you are not keeping the Commandments oh
then it makes sense why a person who
professes Christ and yet does not keep
his
Commandments might fear a judgment
because now oh you're saying there's a
standard in the
Judgment I'm not saying
that that's what the text
says how about this how about this
Malachi CH 3:5 and I will come near to
you to judgment and I will be a swift
witness against the sorcerers and
against adulterers and against false
false um swearers and against those who
oppress their hirling in his wages the
Widow and the fatherless and turn aside
the stranger from his right and fear not
me say the Lord of hosts now some of
youall might be thinking oh that's the
Book of Malachi that's the Old Testament
it's all right now to commit adultery
and be a false swearer and oppose those
or and and and and oppress the hireling
of his wages and the Widow and the
fatherless as well that was Old
Testament stuff Pastor don't you get it
don't you
see and that's why so many Christians
are afraid of the Judgment that's why so
many Christians when when they hear the
idea of a judgment it strikes fear and
Terror in their hearts and they will do
whatever is necessary make video after
video after video write books everything
they possibly can to say any talk of any
kind of investigative judgment is heresy
why
because it's
heresy so God's judgment is heresy yes
why
because when the the real reason
Beloved the real
reason is that when people know they're
not living according
to the standard that Jesus himself has
laid out yeah you have
reason to be
afraid you have reason to be afraid
Matthew 12:36 New Testament y'all but I
say unto you that Every Idle word that
men shall speak they shall give an
account thereof in the day of judgment
how about this James 2:19 thou believeth
there is one God thou doest well the
Devils also believe and tremble you so
you mean Pastor is not just about
believing that there is one God it's not
just about believing in Jesus what the
James said you believe there is one God
that's great the Devils also believe and
tremble they do a little bit more than
you they tremble you're not even
trembling watch what he goes on to say
but will thou know oh vain man that
faith without work works is
dead so I hear a lot of people often say
oh this idea of an investigative
judgment nullifies salvation because
you're saved through faith but James
here is saying you're not just saved by
believing I need you to understand that
faith without works is
dead let's go back to the screen notice
what James goes on to say was not
Abraham Our Father justified by works
when he had offered Isaac his son upon
the
altar I know some of you are are want to
Stone James right
now some of you want to Stone James
right now he just apost he's preaching
heresy he's saying that our Father
Abraham was justified by works that's
heresy let's keep
reading was not Abraham Our Father
justified by works when he had offered
Isaac his son upon the altar see thou
how Faith wrought with his works and by
works Faith was Faith made perfect H and
the scripture saith and the scripture
was fulfilled with saith Abraham
believed God and it was imputed unto him
for righteousness for he was called the
friend of God watch this you see then
how that by works a man is Justified and
not by faith only so listen beloved in
the the reason the reason that God has a
judgment to show the world and to show
angels to show uh the entire
existence who he's going to allow into
heaven is because while some people
profess Faith their
Works say something
different no I'm not keeping your
Commandments I just want to be saved by
faith
only oh man James just said not by faith
only James just said genuine faith will
produce works that are in harmony with
God's
word and now you can begin to see why so
many Christians are afraid of the
Judgment because when you reject the law
of God as binding upon you when you
reject the commandments of Jesus as
binding upon you yeah you're you're
pretty nervous about going into court
you don't want to hear any talk about
judgment you don't want to hear any talk
about a court you just want the case to
have been
tried with no evidence that you're
actually righteous just your confession
I said I believe that should be good
enough Lord right I confess with my
mouth that should be good enough why why
why does it have to be a
judgment H The Book of Matthew chapter
7:15 says beware of false prophets which
come to you in sheep's clothing for
inwardly they are they but inwardly they
are ravening wolves you shall know them
by their fruits do men gather Grapes of
thorns or figs of thistles even so every
good tree bringeth forth good fruit but
a corrupt tree bringeth forth evil fruit
in other words beloved God says that
it's not just your confession it's your
fruit it's your fruit notice again with
me the same chapter same chapter Matthew
7:18 a good tree cannot bring forth evil
fruit neither can a corrupt tree bring
forth good fruit and then he goes on to
say this not everyone that saith unto me
Lord Lord shall enter into the kingdom
of heaven but he that doeth the will of
My Father which is in heaven many will
say to me in that day Lord Lord have we
not prophesied in thy name and have we
not cast out devils in thy name and have
we not done many wonderful Works in thy
name and have we not done many wonderful
videos on YouTube in thy name and he
will then profess unto them I never knew
you depart from me you that work
iniquity and what is Iniquity everyone
according to the Bible iniquity is sin
which according to 1 John 3:4 is the
transgression of the law let's go go to
the screen and look at it the Bible says
hereby we do know that we know him if we
keep his Commandments if we keep his
Commandments we know that we know him
watch this he that saith I know him and
keepeth not his Commandments is a liar
and the truth is not in him now let me
ask y'all a
question how many of you would want to
go to
court if you were a
liar and you knew that you were about to
be
exposed as a
liar you wouldn't want to go to court
would you the Bible says he that says he
knows me and ignores my
Commandments yes it's our right to steal
yes it's our right to kill yeah it's all
right to commit adultery yeah it's all
right to yeah bowing down before giving
ah you know whatever I accept Jesus
though God says that person who
willingly Rejects My law which is the
standard of my judgment in The Mercy
Seat in the sanctuary there is a
something called the Ark of the Covenant
the Ark of the Covenant uh is is was a
box that held the Ten Commandments in it
on top of the Ark was something called
The Mercy Seat which is the Throne of
God God's Throne is established on his
law God's Throne is established the the
the the foundation of God's throne is
his Justice his judgment and so in
rejecting the law of God you are
rejecting the very judgment Throne of
God that's what's
happening but listen y'all cuz you're
like pastor but I can't keep the
Commandments perfectly I'm going to mess
up listen to what the Bible says Ezekiel
20:5 right in the middle of the Ten
Commandments the Bible says Thou shalt
not bow down thyself to them nor serve
them for either the Lord thy God I'm a
jealous God visiting the iniquity of the
fathers upon the children unto the third
and fourth generation of them that of
them that hate me watch this and showing
Mercy unto thousands of them that love
me and keep my Commandments now let me
ask youall a question how many of you
want Mercy how many of you want
Mercy if you want look at me y'all
listen to me if you want to be under The
Mercy Seat of
God remember there is The Mercy Seat and
underneath it is the law of God if you
want to be under the mercy of God that
means you are standing on his
Commandments if you go to court and you
say I know that I'm guilty of breaking
your law but through the indwelling of
by accepting you as my savior and
through the in indwelling of your spirit
I am striving to no longer lie to no
longer live a life of Deceit to no
longer kill I used to be a killer to no
longer commit adultery to no longer bear
false witness to no longer covet Lord
help me to do the and if I fall and I
and I if I fall then you said that that
uh if we confess our sins you're
faithful and just to forgive us our sins
that's a whole different Spirit than I
don't need to keep your Commandments
cause you for you I accepted you at the
cross so why should I keep your
Commandments isn't that works
whole different Spirits y'all whole
different demeanor whole different
Spirit we don't need to be afraid look
at what the Bible says because many of
us now are like well wait a minute if
this judgment thing is true because I've
just been told in my church that there's
no such thing of the Judgment that you
know the Judgment Christians don't have
to worry about it and there's no
judgment for the Christian but if what
you're saying is true Pastor what about
my uncle what about my aunt what about
my
parents what about my grandparents who
came before me who are now gone they
didn't they they didn't know about this
particular commandment or that are they
lost listen to what the Bible says y'all
in Acts chapter 17:30 at times of
ignorance God winked at but now
commandeth all men everywhere to repent
isn't our judge good our judge beloved
is so good because listen let me let me
yeah let me address the elephant in the
room so many Christians are like the Ten
Commandments have done away with and the
reason they're saying that is because
they don't want to keep the Sabbath
because the Sabbath is going to
interfere with what the world does on
Friday nights and on Saturdays busiest
shopping day this and that all the
inconvenience of following that
commandment and plus nobody else is
doing it I would be I would be really
kind of alone in this in my
circles the Bible says God Winks in time
s of ignorance you didn't know your
uncle and Aunt didn't know your mother
didn't know your grandparents didn't
know guess what beloved guess what God's
got them covered if they were genuine
Christians walking in the light that
they had the judge of the universe has
them covered he Winks at their ignorance
is't that
good you don't have to deny what the
word of God says in order to think in
your mind that your that your
grandparents and their parents were
saved you need to do that you don't
God's got everybody the true saints of
God there are there are true saints of
God who didn't have all the light who
didn't understand everything in the
Bible but they lived up to what they
knew and God Winks at what they didn't
know but now God is saying you
know in times of ignorance God Winks but
now when ignorance is swept out the way
he commands men to repent I was wrong on
that let me start keeping this
commandment I was wrong on that let me
stop ignoring this commandment let me
not make the grace of God a
disgrace because God doesn't deal in
disgrace you can't just take the grace
of God and say yeah this means that we
don't need to keep the law because if
there's no law there's no judgment and
that's the reason why many Christians
reject the Judgment because they reject
the law of God which is the standard of
the judgment and they know in not living
according to that law of God they would
then be in danger of the Judgment so
better from my own mental sanity just
say and just believe there is no
judgment that that's gonna make me feel
better and feel more
secure in false
security you may think I'm secure in my
salvation but beloved just because you
think your elephant doesn't make you an
elephant just because you think you're a
follower of Jesus doesn't make you a
follower of Jesus many will say to me in
that day Lord Lord did we not do all
these things and Jesus will say depart
from me you workers of iniquity what is
Iniquity it is sin what is sin it is
transgression of the law of God by their
fruit you shall know
them follow me all listen to what I'm
saying not not listen what I'm saying
listen to what the word of God is saying
so now so
now oh I let me finish the verse I
didn't finish the look let's go back to
the screen let me just do this
again at times of ignorance God winked
but now commandeth all men everywhere to
repent why because he has appointed a
day meaning a time in which he will
judge the world and he will so in the
days of Acts after Jesus's death burial
and
Resurrection in Acts 17 after the de
because some people think oh when Jesus
died on a cross judgment just
disappeared everybody's good now we're
all good now there is no judgment but
the text
says that God will judge the world in
righteousness by that man whom he has
ordained whereof he has given Assurance
unto all men in that he raised him from
the dead be
sure be sure
acts 17 is telling us that a judgment is
coming be sure of it be certain so
here's the question now now that we have
settled hopefully settled that there is
a judgment that Christians need not be
afraid of the Judgment then beloved
there is no reason why any Christian
should be walking around saying an idea
of an investigative judgment is heresy
it's not heresy what's
heresy is denying there's a judgment
what's heresy is denying there is a law
by which the
Judgment
occurs what's heresy is telling other
people don't worry about a judgment and
don't worry about the standard of the
Judgment because as Christians you're
not going to face judgment that's what's
heresy when the Bible tells us over and
over and over again now that's not so so
now that we've got that out the way
because some people well you know what
it's it's it's it's you know how do you
know judgment began at this particular
time listen y'all it the argument is not
over your argument isn't really when did
judgment begin the real argument
is we don't want a
judgment because we're not observing the
standard of the
Judgment that's what's happening y'all
let's just be honest let's speak fr
frankly so when is this judgment when is
this judgment that God speaks of is
going to happen when does this judgment
occur let's go back to the screen and I
want you to note Revelation 14:6 the
Bible says here Revelation 14:6 and I
saw another angel fly in the midst of
Heaven having the Everlasting gospel to
preach unto them that dwell on the earth
and to Every Nation Kindred tongue and
people saying with a loud voice fear God
and give glory to him for the hour of
his judgment is come and worship him
that made Heaven the Earth the sea and
The Fountains of waters according to
this text we see that the Judgment of
God must begin at some point when the
gospel is still going to the world hold
on wait a minute what
Pastor
what I
thought I thought the Judgment occurs
when you die no no no no no the Jud
doesn't occur when you die there is a
second judgment and we're going to deal
with that at another time we can't even
touch that now there is a second there
are there are two
judgments but this judgment that we're
reading about in Revelation 147
occurs when the world is still standing
and the gospel is still being preached
how do we know because the text just
said the hour of his judgment is come
and now notice what happens next and
there followed another Angel saying
Babylon has fallen has fallen that great
City because she made all nations drink
of the wine of the wrath of her
fornication so the second Angel's
message which is about the fall of
Babylon that occurs while the Earth is
still standing how about this the third
Angel followed them saying with a loud
voice if any man worshiped the Beast and
His Image and receive his Mark in his
forehead or in his hand now let me just
stop right here here's what I wanted
want you to see
guys this judgment begins before the
mark of the beast is
manifested did y'all catch that just
now if the first Angel's message comes
first and the third Angel's message
comes
third and the third Angel's message is
about the mark of the beast which has
not occurred yet then the first Angel's
message which occurs before the third
Angel's message must mean
that whatever this whenever the judgment
is it must begin while people are still
living upon the
Earth are y'all following what I'm
saying in fact if we read down just a
few verses later we're going to skip
Revelation 14:10 which talks about the
destruction of the wicked and the smoke
of their torment but now no listen the
very next verse after this here is the
patience of the Saints here are they
that keep the Commandments of God and
have the faith of Jesus wow are you
telling me Pastor the Judgment has
something to do with the Commandments of
God and the faith of Jesus faith and
works
what what come on come back to the
screen for a minute y'all
what first there's a judgment
announcement this judgment begins before
the mark of of the Beast issue which
means that the judgment is going on
while men are still alive and then the
text says here's a description of the
Saints during this time they do two
things they have two things the faith of
Jesus we are saved by faith and the
Commandments of God our
works determine our works
reveal our faith
wow
wow y'all y'all y'all put a
um put this in
here I was going to say put b a d Bible
all day but that's bad and that bad
doesn't sound good so just go ahead and
put Bible all day in the chat for me
please
this is
Bible this is
Bible so the Bible tells us that in this
judgment the Saints are described as
those who keep the Commandments of
God and have the faith of Jesus like
James was saying Faith mingled with
works and then right after this the
Bible says in the very next verse verse
14 I looked and behold a white cloud and
upon the cloud one sat like unto the son
of man having on his head a Golden Crown
and in his hand a sharp sickle and
another angel came out of the temple
crying with a loud voice to him that sat
on the cloud thrust in thy sickle and
reap for thy time is for the time is
come to reap for the Harvest of the
earth is ripe so in other words beloved
before the second coming of Jesus the
mark of the beast must happen but before
the mark of the beast happens there is a
judgment which means the Judgment of God
the Judgment of God the Judgment of God
in which he vindicates the righteous and
condemns the wicked
overturns the work of the wicked must
occur before Jesus returns it must occur
at some point while men are living upon
the Earth and listen we're not going to
get into today when that occurred we're
not going to get into what time that was
or what time that will be we're not
because that's not even the point of
this message the point of this message
is why are so many Christians afraid of
a judgment and we're seeing why because
so many Christians claim the faith of
Jesus but deny the Commandments of God
and as a result they are
afraid they are
afraid of the Judgment that's why but
you don't need to be afraid of the
Judgment if you have perfect love
perfect love cast out fear and Jesus
said if you love me keep my Commandments
why because the Commandments are the
basis by which your faith is actually
demonstrated
faith without works is trouble in a
court faith without works is trouble in
a
court he that sat on the cloud thrusting
his sickle on the Earth and the Earth
was reaped beloved Jesus is coming to
reap the faithful the Judgment occurs
before Jesus comes again the second time
this is clearly laid out in Revelation
chapter 14 but let's see if we can get a
little bit more let's see if we can
pinpoint this a little bit
further let's go to the Book of Daniel
let's go to the Book of Daniel and and
and I need you to follow this um all
right can we come back do y'all see me
on the screen still or
no we're going to go to Daniel chapter 7
but I just want to make sure that you
could see me on screen so just put a one
in the chat if you see me on screen all
right I don't know if you see me on
screen but I'm just going to keep going
Daniel 7 vers1 in the first year now
follow this you guys Daniel 7 verse1 in
the first year of Bel shazar king of
Babylon Daniel had a dream and visions
of his head upon his bed and he wrote
the dream and told the sum of the matter
uh the Bible says Daniel spake and said
I saw in my in Vision By Night and
behold the for Winds of the heaven
strove upon the great sea and four ba
great beasts came up from the sea
diverse one from another and I I'm just
going to I'm going to we're just going
to kind of run through this the first
was like a lion the second was like a
bear the third was a leopard and the
fourth Beast had 10 horns had 10 horns
now from Bible prophecy we understand
that I okay I think y'all can just see
my
slides all right so we'll see what
happens maybe there's technical
difficulty well just listen to my voice
just listen to my voice okay so you got
these four beasts that come up out of
the sea a lion a bear a leopard and then
there fourth nondescript Beast we
understand that a beast represents a
kingdom in Bible prophecy who are these
four beasts they're Babylon they're
metap Persia Greece Rome those are the
beasts in their order Babylon Meo Persia
Greece Rome the Bible says the fourth
Beast had 10 horns s and then another
little horn comes up out of this fourth
Beast we understand as Bible prophecy
students that this fourth Beast is Rome
and that this little horn represents the
papal power that dominated during the
Dark Ages the Bible tells us that this
power ruled for
1260 years 1,60 prophetic years you find
that in Daniel 7:25
time times and half a Time
1,260 years this is not an Adventist
interpretation you can look and see
other Scholars other commentaries that
have mentioned that this time period
symbolizes years not days and we can
understand that because the papacy
dominated for that time they dominated
for over a thousand years rising up out
of Rome now why is this so important why
am I laying this out for you we just
kind of did a juic down version of
Daniel chapter 7 but here's why this is
so
significant the reason that is
significant is because right after
Daniel sees this little horn dominating
for
1,260 years note what he says in verse n
he says I beheld till so what is he
beholding what is he
beholding he is beholding the little
horn the little horn dominates for
1,260 years he says I'm beholding this
little horn meaning I'm beholding him
for this time
until Thrones were cast down now I want
you to to to to think about this for a
moment with me let me let me just finish
reading Thrones were cast down and the
Ancient of Days did sit took his seat
whose garment was white as snow and the
hair of his head like pure wool his
Throne was like the fiery flame and his
wheels as burning fire there we go uh um
yeah let's go back to that image his
wheel is burning fire next
verse a fiery stream issued and came
forth from before him thousand thousands
minutes unto him and 10,000 times 10,000
stood before him the Judgment was set
and the books were open now pause for a
second y'all pause for a
second the Judgment was set
and the books were open Thrones were
cast down so here's what's going on I
want you to see this now okay Jesus okay
Babylon Meo Persia Greece Rome Jesus
comes during the Roman Empire he's he
dies is buried resurrected ascends to
Heaven during the Roman
Empire the vision sees the fall of
Rome and then the rise of 10 horns or 10
smaller kingdoms out of Rome and then a
little horn after the rise of these T
this is way after the death barrial and
resurrection of
Jesus then Daniel sees this little horn
dominating for over a thousand years and
it is after listen to me it is after
this Thousand-Year period which ended
sometime around
1798 that is the time period of the 1260
years and different comment may have a
little different time in terms of when
it actually began but but it ends
sometime around the late 1700s and the
text is telling
us that sometime after this domination
of this little horn Daniel
Sees
God as it
were setting sitting down in a almost as
if a judge has walked walked into a
courtroom yo y I love the
Bible I love the
Bible Daniel Sees God the
Father taking a seat almost as if a
courtroom is being set up like a a new
room a special
room sometime after 1798 sometime after
the rain
of this little horn
power Daniel's Daniel's view shifts to
heaven and he sees the
father entering into this almost like as
if he's entering into this courtroom to
take a seat to take a seat I thought
God's always been sitting on his throne
to take a seat
as if a court as if a trial is about to
start and we don't have to guess that
because the text just told us the
Judgment was set and the books were
opened so now watch this this judgment
which is the same judgment being
described in Daniel in Revelation
chapter 14 occurs sometime after
1798 but before for the second coming of
Jesus now y'all
listen right now it's not about
pinpointing when that started that's not
even the point of this
message that's not the point of this
message we're not here to say to to I'm
not here to tell you right now I can but
I'm not here to tell you right now this
is when the Judgment started all I'm
trying to say is we know the Judgment
this judgment starts After the Dark Ages
but it begins oh starts After the Dark
Ages but before the second coming of
Jesus before the mark of the beast
before Babylon has
fallen and it's a judgment designed it's
a judgment designed to
overturn the injust decisions made by
professed Christians who were burning
other Christians at the stake for not
believing what they believe
doctrinally it is overturning the
Judgment of so many who have died who
symbolically speaking their souls are
under the altar that's a symbolic
reference in the Book of Revelation
chapter 6 how long oh Lord will thou not
judge God says don't worry about it the
judgment is coming and now we read in
Daniel 7 hey this judgment happens it
began sometime after the Dark
Ages how do we know this come on let's
go back to Daniel chapter 7 and we're
almost there guys we're almost done
please follow I beheld them because of
the voice the great words of of the
great words which the horns speak I
beheld even till the Beast was slain did
is that is the fourth beast and his body
destroyed and given to the burning
flames as concerning the rest of the
beasts they had their their Dominion
taken away yet their lies were prolonged
for a time and a season well beloved we
know when Jesus returns that nobody's
lies are prolong for a time in a season
this is talking about an event in the
past what Daniel is seeing here is a
judgment that is set up while the
kingdoms of this Earth are still in
existence and now watch this y'all in
the same
chapter in the same chapter verse 13
here's what it says I saw in the night
visions and
behold one like the son of man came with
the clouds of heaven and came to the
Ancient of Days and they brought him
near before him hold on wait a
minute wait
one
second it's almost like the text seems
to be saying that Jesus came well where
is he coming man I mean at first you
would think he's coming to the Earth
whoa so wait a minute is Jesus actually
coming wait a minute maybe Jesus is
coming to the Earth in this text maybe
sometime after 1798 maybe as they were
studying this back and sit back in those
times they thought whoa the son of man
is coming to the Earth but no no no no
no that's not what the son of man was
doing cuz it couldn't refer to the
crucifixion and Jesus sending to Heaven
why because we got Babylon meter Persia
Greece Rome the little the 10 horns the
little horn and then this judgment scene
where the father takes his seat and the
son is being brought before him almost
as if they are moving to a new location
both of them not one of them both of
them are now going into this new phase
of ministry as it were or something to
do with the salvation of mankind in
which a judgment is being set
up a
courtroom is being
seated you would be it would be okay if
you were mistaken in thinking that this
coming of the son of man was the coming
of Jesus to the Earth but that's not
what it that's not what it's talking
about y'all it's talking about this
entering into a a new into this this
judge this judgment scene in which the
the the
courtrooms and faulty decisions of men
against the people of
God is about to be
overturned
wow wow come back with me to the screen
Daniel 7:21 I beheld the same horn made
war with the Saints and prevailed
against them until
the Ancient of Days came and was given
to the and judgment was given to the
Saints and the time came that they
possessed the the kingdom of the most
high Daniel 7 is explaining Daniel is
explaining what he saw in the vision
when the Ancient of Days came this is a
judgment scene that is occurring before
the second coming of Jesus it's
happening in heaven note what the text
says in Daniel 7:26 but the Judgment
shall sit and they shall take away his
Dominion to consume and destroy it unto
the end meaning this judgment continues
onto the end meaning this judgment is
not something that happens at the end or
after the end it continues onto the
end all right
y'all all
right John Gil speaking on this verse
says this
John Gil's commentary says this up until
the Ancient of Days came notice what
John Gil who was a Baptist Minister says
about this text y'all not locally by
change of place he being the omnipresent
God but in a providential way to check
and put a stop to the power and
prevalency of the little horn over the
Saints for this is determinist or end of
that which puts a period to it for when
the Ancient of Days come comes in the
exertion of his power and Providence he
will come and sit as judge upon this
little horn or Antichrist and judge and
condemn and punish it
y'all John Gil says this coming of the
Ancient of
Days H is not locally as if he's coming
to the Earth but it represents a check
on the power of the little
horn
wow speaking of going on he says and
judgment was given to the Saints of the
most high their characters Vindicated
from all calumny and false aspersions
their adversaries condemned and punished
and power and dominion and and Authority
given to them with Christ you
guys I mean we could go all day long but
let's talk about this come on y'all come
back to the screen we're g to talk about
this why the denial why the denial why
the heavy denial against the Judgment
it's not because Advent is say that
judgment began in
1844 which happens to be after this
1,260 years but before the second coming
of Jesus that's not why people really
are against this idea of the Judgment
they're against the idea of the Judgment
because the Judgment requires them to
acknowledge the
standard the standard which is the law
of God which they reject so God says
listen I want you to stop rejecting my
standard my law I'm coming to you in
Mercy I'm sending a message to you to
fear God and give glory to him for the
hour of his judgment is come I'm giving
a message to you I'm sending a message
to you calling you my people to come out
of Babylon why are you why am I calling
you my people because I know you're
genuine I know you're honest I know
you're sincere but you're being told
this by your pastors and your ministers
and the YouTube videos that you're
watching that oh don't listen to this
don't listen to them because the law of
God's been done away with and we're no
longer under the law and blah blah blah
but listen I'm trying to tell
you that in this
judgment if you reject the standard of
the Judgment you're rejecting the one
who gave the
law you see most many Christians believe
in this thing called once saved always
saved and the real rejection of the law
of God
God is because of this one- saved always
saved teaching if I accepted Jesus with
my mouth and believe in with my heart
then I'm saved and I can never be lost
don't show me the law because the law is
condemning me and I don't want to feel
condemned the law is telling me that
while I claim Jesus if I'm still living
in adultery if I'm still bearing false
witness against people whether that be
online or anywhere else if I'm still
lying if I'm still lying if I'm still
stealing no I'm not getting into heaven
and I don't want to hear that what
sounds better to me is that once I said
back then about 15 years ago that I
believe in Jesus it doesn't matter if
I'm living in an adult in an adulterous
relationship it doesn't matter if if I
lie it doesn't matter I don't need even
need to ask for forgiveness of those
things because I'm already saved and I'm
not saved by my works I'm saved by faith
in Jesus that's a very comforting
lie but that's what the devil's pushing
how do we know it's a lie come back with
me to the screen the Bible says in Ro
Revelation 3:5 he that overcometh the
same shall be clothed in white rment and
I will not blot out his name out of the
book of life you mean your name can be
blotted out of The Book of Life yes
indeed y'all your name can be blotted
out of The Book of Life in fact Jesus
also said this the son of man shall send
forth send forth his angels and they
Shall Gather out of his kingdom all
things that offend which means that in
his kingdom there are those who offend
in his kingdom in his kingdom that is in
his church there are those who claim
Jesus and yet are living how they want
to live Jesus says when I come
again when my angels come they will be
taken out of my kingdom and be cast into
into fire
that says to
me that once saved always saved is one
of the biggest heresies that's the
heresy the heresy is that Jesus is bound
to save you just because you said these
words I believe in Jesus with all my
heart just because you said that Jesus
is bound to save you and the law of
God's done away with let me tell y'all
something if the Ten Commandments are
done away with then everyone that was
ever condemned by it ought to ought to
have a free pass into
heaven so when marijuana in certain
places was was was illegal and people
would go to jail for having marijuana or
selling Mar whatever and now in many
places where that law has been
overturned yeah there're people that you
can't be H they're no longer being held
by a law that is no longer valid so if
the Ten Commandments is no longer valid
then everyone that was lost everyone
that would have been lost for not
abiding by the law lying stealing
killing if that Law's done away with
then there's nothing stopping anybody
from getting into heaven except do you
believe in Jesus I believe in him with
all my heart and then we're good to
go 66 books of the
Bible just to tell us that if we say
these magic words I believe in in Jesus
then we're good to
go
really
really all right guys I got two more
things to share with you and we're done
Genesis 61 and2 and it came to pass when
men began to multiply on the face of the
Earth that daughters were born unto them
that the sons of God saw the daughters
of men that they were fair and they took
them wives of which they all chose and
the Lord said my spirit shall not always
strive with man for that he is also
flesh yet his day shall be 120 years let
me say this to y'all let me say this to
you I'm G share my last point was there
a judgment message in the days of
Noah did God say to Noah I want you to
preach how long did Noah preach everyone
put it in the chat for me please how
long did did Noah preach the Judgment
message do you think halfway into those
120 years that people were probably like
man that judgment message it's not
happening no been no
been that boy been preaching that
message for the last 60 years no no
judgment
coming y'all been saying this since 1844
a't no judgment coming it's not no
judgment
time it's not going to rain fire what
are you talk come on man we're gonna be
raptured out of here we're gonna be all
right
120 years 120
years and so many people began to listen
to the popular opinions of the day yeah
man Noah he a cult he and his family
they're a
cult they got this whole thing about the
door gonna be shut probation gonna
close
come where is that in the Bible oh yeah
they didn't have a Bible in those days
but y'all get the idea
right but there came a day when the door
was closed and he who was righteous was
righteous still and he who was wicked
had to be Wicked
still and beloved let me tell you don't
let the same thing happen because it's
happening right now people are making
decisions sealing themselves off from
salvation by determining in their
mind that they do not need to get into
the ark just like no it didn't Jo no I'm
not getting in the ark there's something
in the in the they did not I'm not
getting in the Ark of the Covenant I
ain't getting in the ark The Ten
Commandments that Arc is done away with
man we don't need the ark we do not need
the ark but beloved y'all need to
understand the ark is where the mercy
seat is and you get rid of the
Ark you can't disconnect The Mercy Seat
from the ark you get rid of the mercy
you get rid of the Ark you've gotten rid
of The Mercy Seat because God does not
show Mercy to those who do not keep his
Commandments he told us in the
text he told us in the text and now let
me conclude beloved let me conclude with
this with this last and most beautiful
point I need y'all to understand
this when when Lucifer rebelled in
heaven God said these words to him
Ezekiel 2817 thine heart was lifted up
because of thy Beauty thou has corrupted
thy re thy wisdom by reason of thy
brightness I will cast thee to the
ground I will lay thee before Kings this
statement is a statement of judgment
towards Lucifer I'm going to do all
these things to you and I'm G to lay you
before Kings now why did God say that
why did God cast Lucifer Out of Heaven
to this Earth according to Revelation
chapter 12 he was cast out into the
Earth why was that done why was he put
here
if you go back to the Bible Deuteronomy
19:1 16-1 17 says this if a false
witness rise up against any man to
testify against him that which is wrong
then both the men between whom the
controversy is shall stand before the
Lord before the priests and the judges
which shall be in those
days and the judges shall make diligent
Inquisition and behold if the witness be
a false witness and has testified
falsely against his brother then shall
you do unto him as he had thought to
have done unto his brother so shall you
put away the evil from among you and
those which remain shall hear and fear
and shall henceforth commit no more any
such evil among you here's what God
says God lays out a principle where he
says if controversy arises between two
parties between two people there must be
a third party that will judge between
the
two so in heaven when Satan and his
angels are fighting against God and His
angels there is no third party this is
why Lucifer was not immediately
judged so the question then becomes why
does God cast Lucifer out to this
earth why does he cast him out
here could the reason
be that we are the
kings that God has called to
judge the devil and his
angels we don't have to speculate please
note the screen 1 Corinthians chapter 6
1-3 dare any of you having a matter
against another go to law before the
unjust and not before the Saints do you
not know that the Saints shall judge the
world and if the world shall be judged
by you are you unworthy to judge judge
the smallest matters
know you not that we shall
judge
Angels wait a minute
what did God just say that mankind is
going to judge Angels is that what he
just said is that what God just said is
that what the Bible just said Yes Y'all
the Bible just said that the Bible just
said that mankind the redeemed are going
to be the jurors that judge the devil
and his
angels well when is that going to happen
come again with me this is our last text
y'all Revelation chap 20 verse1 the
Bible says and I saw an angel come down
from heaven having the key of the of the
bottomless pit and a great chain in his
hand and he laid hold on the dragon that
old serpent which is the devil and Satan
and bound him a thousand years and cast
him into the bottomless pit and shut him
up and set a seal upon him that he
should deceive the Nations no more till
the Thousand Years should be fulfilled
and after that he must be loose a little
season listen to this and I saw Thrones
and they sat upon them and judgment was
given unto them and I saw the souls of
them that were beheaded for the
witnesses Jesus of Jesus and for the
word of God and which had not worshiped
the Beast neither his image neither had
received his Mark upon their foreheads
or in their hands and they lived and
reigned with Christ a thousand years
come on y'all let us break this down
in Revelation chapter
20 the Saints are resurrected this is
obviously the second coming of Jesus and
here the Bible says the Saints reign
with Jesus in heaven for a thousand
years and judgment is given unto them
who are the Saints going to be
judging they're going to be judging the
devil and his angels but now watch this
the Saints are going to heaven to do
this meaning they are going into the
Supreme Court of
heaven but in order listen to me y'all
in order to be a part of that judgment
in order to be one of the jurors in that
judgment you must first be
chosen as a
jurer wait a minute Pastor are you
saying that that judgment that we read
about back in Daniel chapter 7 is
God selecting the
jurry are you saying that in that
judgment when the books are open and
Jesus and the father as it were are set
up in this courtroom like place just ju
just imagine it with me that the f the
son is is brought before the father who
takes his seat on the throne by the
way in the Book of Leviticus chapter
16 God tells Moses once a year I will
appear on The Mercy Seat I will appear
almost as if God was taking his seat on
the day of atonement as a symbol of
judgment as a symbol of a courtroom
scene once a year he wasn't just sitting
on the on the mercy seat in the most
holy place all the time it says he would
appear on The Mercy Seat on that day how
do we know this because the whole time
he was either in the cloud in the
wilderness in the cloud or in the pillar
of fire but on the day of atonement he
appears almost as if he's taking his
seat in the most holy
place the day of atonement was a was a
was a sin symbol of judgment to the
ancient Jews and to the Jews to this
day so could it be that that scene in
Daniel 7 this judgment that began
sometime after the little horn in in
1798 but before the second coming could
it be that the per one of the purposes
of that
judgment is to select the
jurry now what how do you get selected
as a jurer
listen to me y'all there's several
things but here's a key thing a juror
must be a law-abiding citizen of the
kingdom of
heaven and if you are arguing right now
that the law of God doesn't stand how
can God use you as a jurer where the law
is his
standard how can God use you as a juror
if you would argue on the the devil's
behalf if you would argue on the
wicked's behalf that hey just because
they didn't keep the law shouldn't mean
cuz I mean I didn't keep the law and I'm
here and that's why those that keep the
law those that don't keep the law those
that don't keep his Commandments
Revelation 22:14 blessed are they that
do his Commandments that they may have
right to the tree of life and may enter
in through the gates into the city you
guys by
Bible all
day the devil doesn't want jurors in
heaven because he knows that they are
going to condemn him and that's why he's
busy leading so many potential jurors to
disqualify themselves by simply saying
there's no judgment there's no law we're
good to go all you need to do is confess
Jesus you get to go
so what is my
appeal my appeal is this you don't need
to be afraid of the
Judgment if you're afraid of the
Judgment it's because something's not
right if you love God and you're keeping
his Commandments you have no reason to
be afraid of the Judgment perfect love
cast out fear Jesus said if you love me
keep my
Commandments God's appeal is that he
wants you to be a jurer
don't worry about your your parents your
grandparents
whatever if they lived up to all the
light that they had they will be jurors
even though they didn't keep the Sabbath
even though they didn't know about it
they didn't even though the other
command they didn't know about it God's
got them don't worry about them worry
about
you worry about
you God says I'm going to make you Kings
and Prest priests third Angel Kings and
Priests for a thousand years we are the
kings that are going to be that are
going to judge Lucifer think about the
awesomeness of that but how can you
judge him there if you're playing
devil's advocate
here and beloved if the Bible calls
Satan the Lawless one and you are on his
bandwagon saying there is no law law we
don't need a law you live by the law not
understanding that the law that was done
away with at the cross is not the Ten
Commandments it is the law of sacrifices
and ordinances those things are done
away with that's why we don't do those
things anymore because Christ Our lamb
has been sacrificed for us but if you
think Christ's death on the cross
literally means that it's now that the
Ten Commandments is done away with
that's not good jury that's not a
that's those kind of jurors will argue
on behalf of
Satan they will argue on behalf of the
wicked and God's not going to have that
so put a one in the chat put a one in
the chat if you're saying today Lord I
want I need to be a juror I want to be a
juror I know that I cannot do it in my
strength but
Lord lead me to accept your
sacrifice and lead me to have your law
written on my heart as is clearly stated
in the New Testament as part of the New
Covenant I will write my
laws upon your heart help me Lord not to
be afraid of the
Judgment help me Lord to have your law
written on my
heart and perfect my love that I may
have boldness in the day of judgment if
that's your desire put that one in the
chat as I close in prayer heavenly
father thank you for speaking to us
thank you for taking us through the
Bible the Bible and only the
Bible thank you for showing us Lord we
didn't even talk about when this
judgment begins but Lord we know the
judgment is going on right now we know
when it began many others do not but
right now that's not even the important
thing the important thing is to
understand that judgment occurs before
you come again which means we need to
understand the emphasis and the focus of
that judgment that it is to redeem the
meek
and condemn the
wicked and Lord if we have nothing to
hide then we have nothing to
fear thank you Lord for speaking to us
today in Jesus name we pray
amen for those of you that would like to
get a copy of the slides you will see on
this next link where you can scan to
either get a copy of the slides to
connect with LM or to follow me on my
social media or to follow living mana on
it social media media um we're going to
put up the link in the chat for the
Afterglow discussion we invite everyone
to be a part of it uh and um may God
bless you um and may God keep
you until we meet again I will see you
all next week by God's grace not next
week but the week after and may God
bless you and keep you
amen thank you for for joining us today
if this is your first time worshiping
with us please check out our website at
Living mana. Church we are not just here
for Sabbath service we have weekly
programming too that covers mental
health physical health weekly prayer
service Financial Health and proving the
existence of God it is our desire that
our programming will continue to bless
you please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the Gospel of Jesus Christ
[Music]
right e